[LESTRADE] The first
victim was a prostitute,
last seen with a john.
He's been described as blond,
fair-skinned, and standing
about six feet tall.
When the body was found,
she was barely recognisable.
Her throat was slit.
And her internal organs had
been meticulously removed.
Then, a week later,
another prostitute was seen
with a man who had
a swarthy complexion.
Additionally, this
individual was shorter than
the first suspect at
five and a half feet tall.
Immediately afterward,
she was killed in
an identical manner.
Based on the eyewitness reports,
we surmised that one of the two
men is the Whitechapel killer.
Then our investigation
took a twist.
A man calling himself
"Jack the Ripper"
stepped forth, claiming
credit for both murders.
[HOLMES]
Just one question.
You built all of
this for me, Lestrade?
[LESTRADE]
Naturally. Nothing worse than
an unengaging presenter.
I'll ask once again.
Help me catch this vile criminal
before he adds more
to his grim tally.
[LESTRADE]
Holmes, please!
I'll pass.
[WATSON grunts]
[JACK] Young Will,
you already have suspicions
regarding the
identity of the culprit?
Yes, the real killer
is actually a group.
Organized crime to be specific.
[GROUP grunts]
You're basing that
on what exactly?
[WILLIAM] First of all,
ask yourself why the killers
would claim to be
Jack the Ripper
and write to the newspapers.
It's simple.
Their objective is to
have a platform for
their criminal acts.
In short, a means of stirring
up fear among the citizens.
As for adopting the
maestro's old nickname,
it was likely an
odd coincidence.
Any name would
have been sufficient,
so long as it stoked dread.
Thus, it's presumable
killing the prostitutes
wasn't their goal
but simply a means to
furthering their ultimate plan.
These killings were
done for dramatic effect.
As we've established,
fanning the flames of
terror was the first step,
but there was also
another objective at play.
And what objective is that?
Revolt.
To incite a battle between
the town's Vigilance
Committee and the Yard.
Once the two sides begin
to clash, it'll escalate.
Setting off a proletarian
revolution within Britain.
[SOLDIERS yell]
Indeed. Such an act is
an enormous undertaking.
The difficulty of one
person carrying it out
would be unimaginable.
[WILLIAM] These culprits,
they've fashioned
a fictional devil and
called him "Jack the Ripper."
Setting the stage for
the Vigilance Committee
to take up arms.
If another murder occurs,
the results will be disastrous.
Conflict between the
Yard and the citizenry
will be unavoidable
and will serve as the
catalyst for an uprising.
If that's true, we have a
problem. Since they're a group,
it'll be hard rounding them up
at the same time and place.
[WILLIAM]
Not to worry.
It'll be a test for the
Moriarty Plan... our goal.
Hm.
[GUARD 16A]
Hm? Huh?
[CIVILIAN 16A growls]
[GUARD 16A growls]
[GUARD 16A]
Hm.
[yelping]
Whew, it's just
a cat, that's all.
Huh?
[gasps]
[whistle sounds]
[CIVILIANS panting]
[POLICE panting]
You expect us to let
the Yard handle this case?
This is our town, and
we'll protect it ourselves!
[POLICE gasp]
[POLICE growl]
[CROWD growls]
[WOMAN 16A screams]
What's that?!
[POLICE gasp]
[chuckles]
- -[CROWD gasps]
- -[JACK cackles]
[JACK] My presence
stills the crying child!
I'm Jack the Ripper!
I've witnessed
the strangest things
from the rooftops and alleys.
War is brewing in Whitechapel.
I certainly hope you didn't
expect me to sit it out.
- -[CROWD gasps]
- -[JACK] By all means, proceed.
While you fight one another,
I can kill to
my heart's content!
[JACK cackling]
[JACK grunts]
[CROWD gasps]
[JACK] What's wrong? No bother
in letting me run free?
[CROWD gasps]
- -[CIVILIAN 16E grunts]
- -[CROWD shouts]
[POLICEMAN 16B] After him, lads!
We can't let him escape!
Goes for us, too!
[CIVILIANS]
Yeah!
[MORAN]
So that's it.
The old man's playing the
common enemy to both sides,
unifying the Yard and
the Vigilance Committee,
not dividing them.
Yes.
A favour, Fred.
Go to the morgue and procure
three autopsied corpses.
Consider it done.
I'll prepare some stage
blood for the performance, too.
[WILLIAM]
Moran and Bonde,
I need you to pick up
some weapons from Herder.
Who is this Herder?
A friend of ours
with probably the
biggest weapon
stockpile in all London.
Once the actual Jack the Ripper
shows up in the flesh,
the criminals are sure to
gather together so as to
plan out their next
move in response.
That's when we'll strike.
But how are we going to
uncover the location
of the rendezvous?
[WILLIAM] That's where
Albert enters the equation.
We'll consult military
intelligence for answers.
Maestro, until we can confirm
the location of their assembly,
I'll need you
to buy us some time.
Happy to. A game of tag,
or rather hide and seek.
[MORAN]
No offense to the old man,
but between the Yard
and Vigilance Committee,
we're talking 300 men,
and if he can't kill anyone--
Absolutely no killing
and I'd like you to refrain
from harming anyone as well.
That's a pretty tall
order you know.
I'm not sure I could
last for ten minutes.
Well, I reckon I could
run for half an hour.
[MORAN]
Hm?
[WILLIAM]
Two hours... if you can.
But I need you to hold out for
one hour at the very minimum.
[POLICEMAN 16C]
There he goes!
[CIVILIAN 16E]
Hold it right there, you rotter!
[JACK panting]
[POLICEMAN 16D grunting]
[POLICEMAN 16D groans]
[JACK]
Young Will,
this plan you concocted
is positively insane.
[JACK grunts]
[CIVILIAN 16D]
Take aim!
[JACK gasps]
[JACK chuckles]
His cloak deflected it!
Is it armoured? Stop him!
[JACK] Even though the
weight is a slight drawback,
I can't complain.
At least it's not hindering
me from my mission.
One, keep running.
Second of all, no killing.
And third, don't get captured.
My role is to do nothing
but buy time until all our
enemies are in one place.
There he is! I've got him!
[CIVILIAN 16F yelps]
What?
How did that happen?
My gun went off by itself!
[POLICEMAN 16E]
Give me that! I'll do it!
[JACK chuckles]
Looks like our sharpshooter's
better than yours.
I'm impressed you can hit them
at this range
without a scope.
[MORAN] What? You expected me
to use that pirate spyglass?
Wait. More of them!
One at two o'clock
and another at ten!
[MORAN]
Yeah, I see them.
We're in the clear.
Doesn't seem like any of them
have the faintest idea
they've been sniped.
[HERDER chuckles] So, in
other words, a rousing success.
Since it's an
enhanced prototype,
my presence was
required in the field
in case certain
disruptions were to occur.
Fortunately, looks like my
services weren't required.
Nah, fine gun.
But the trajectory
tends to slice--
nothing you can't fix, Herder.
[HERDER]
You don't say?
It appears some
fine-tuning is in order.
[MORAN]
All in all, I'm impressed.
The firing's incredibly silent.
[HERDER]
As I designed it to be.
Just make sure you
bring it back in one piece.
Hard to extract data
when it's broken.
Please, that happened once.
The old man must be
pretty worn out by now.
Let's go and back him up.
Right-o.
[JACK panting]
[POLICEMAN 16C]
Over here!
[CIVILIAN 16F]
Hold it!
[JACK]
Huh?
[CIVILIANS]
[POLICE]
Twenty people in front of me,
a mob on my tail.
What now? The alley
looks like my only escape.
But is it?
[JACK] Come on, Fred!
Give me a sign!
Which way?
[JACK]
Straight ahead? You're sure?
Seize him!
[JACK] Very well, straight then!
[JACK grunting]
[CROWD gasps]
[JACK groans]
[CIVILIAN 16G]
He got past us?
[POLICEMAN 16G]
He is a monster!
[JACK]
Now, I see.
If I had gone that way, they
would have beaten me senseless.
[JACK]
Thank you, Fred. You saved me.
[POLICEMAN 16H]
Reporting in!
He's heading down the
street, Chief Inspector!
Good. Roll out
the welcome wagon!
He screws with the Yard,
we'll show him what happens.
There's no way! Is that...
...a Gatling gun?!
[GROUP gasping]
[JACK panting]
[gasps]
[JACK grunts]
[JACK groans]
[ARTERTON]
More!
Don't stop firing! I want
him turned into Swiss cheese!
[MORAN] It's no good.
Thing's built too sturdy.
No way I can disable it.
I might get it to misfire
if I could get a
bullet down that barrel.
But the angle's
wrong from up here.
[gasps] I have an idea!
Follow me!
[MORAN grunts]
[JACK panting]
[BONDE]
[MORAN grunts]
[MORAN]
How unorthodox,
but then again,
that's your style.
[MORAN]
Ready.
Huh?
[POLICE yell]
Whew.
[chuckles]
[BOTH chuckle]
[POLICE groaning, coughing]
[MILVERTON]
I don't know what party's
instigated this chaos,
but the tide has turned.
It's bad!
We didn't account
for a fake showing up!
The entire plan's upside down!
[MILVERTON]
Yes.
This affair has left me
deeply troubled, as well.
Far from what I expected
when I took the job.
All that work building up the
mythological "Jack the Ripper"
through the power of the media.
[MILVERTON] And in a single
night.
He has dissolved the conflict we
orchestrated between
the Vigilance Committee and the
Yard.
[JACK grunts, groans]
[FRED]
Master.
[JACK]
Fred, are you...?
You'll want to head
on through that door.
You can reach the
sewer from there.
Leave the rest to me.
[JACK]
Right. You're on now.
[gasps] He's this way!
In the alley!
[POLICEMAN 16C]
The monster's down here!
[CIVILIAN 16F]
Hold it, Jack!
[JACK sighs, groans]
[JACK]
Ah, I may be getting old.
But, still. I bought
you your hour, William.
[MAN 16A grunts]
Confound it all!
Our plan is ruined!
The vigilantes and the Yard
were just moments away from
going at each other's throats.
Keep your head about you.
Another dead prostitute
will turn the situation
right back around.
He's right.
Nothing will save those
power-hungry elites from us.
We'll send them
straight to hell!
Quiet.
[MAN 16A gasps]
Oi, kill the lights!
[MAN 16B blows]
Hell, you say?
It's been deserted...
...and all of its devils...
...are right here.
[MAN 16D]
All right, who are you blokes?
[WILLIAM]
James Moriarty, or perhaps
it'll be simpler for you if
I just say the Lord of Crime.
You're the Lord of Crime?
[WILLIAM] And we are here
to deliver your punishment
for your Jack the Ripper scheme.
Those women's souls
cry out for vengeance.
He really knows what's going on.
[MAN 16C]
A moment.
[footsteps]
You are trying to plunge
this country into chaos.
That is to say to start a
revolution--the same as us.
You of all people must
understand our motives.
At the expense of
a few useless dregs,
we are on the
verge of delivering
a stunning blow to this
sick, corrupt nation.
Imagine, if we were
to work together,
could we not make our
sublime vision a reality?
[WILLIAM] Are you saying,
for the sake of revolution,
you think nothing of
mercilessly preying on
those poor souls
weaker than you?
As is our right, sir!
The strong eat the weak
and this is no different!
The law of the jungle is
eternal,
and guides the natural world and
all its workings.
[chuckles] Is that so?
I am relieved to
hear you say that.
Then by your own reasoning,
you'll have no quarrel when we
mercilessly take your lives,
since as you've stated,
the strong eat the weak.
[BOTH gasp]
Why, you!
[MAN 16C]
If that's your response...
Carve 'em up, boys!
Louis, there's eight. Ready?
Yes. We'll have eight corpses.
[MAN 16A grunts]
[MAN 16A groans]
[MAN 16E yells]
[BOTH chuckle]
[MAN 16G yells]
[MAN 16G groans]
They're beasts!
We'll be killed!
Quick! Go around the back!
We'll escape on the boat!
[MAN 16F]
Right!
[WILLIAM grunts]
[groans] All that
blood for nothing.
As long as those
three chaps survive,
the plan can take root
and start over! [cackles]
[WILLIAM chuckles]
[WILLIAM] And do you suppose
while you assembled
we sat idly by?
Wh-Whatcha mean?
[WILLIAM]
Now,
which do you think is faster?
The speed of their heels,
or a lit fuse?
Care to bet?
[MEN panting]
I see the exit!
Nearly there!
We're home free!
[FRED grunts]
Moran.
Yeah, that was our signal.
The mission's over.
[LOUIS]
All that remains are the bodies.
You're sure you
want to leave them here?
Yes, the Yard will arrive soon.
And eventually Holmes will
inspect the scene as well.
[WILLIAM]
Based on what I know,
he is certain to figure out
the full story behind this case.
When he does, I'd like to
learn what his reaction is.
[LOUIS]
I assume by "reaction,"
you mean when it comes
to an inconvenient truth,
or a convenient lie,
which will he choose?
[WILLIAM]
That is the question.
[MILVERTON]
Is that--?
If I recall correctly, his name
is William James Moriarty.
Second son of
the Moriarty family
and young mathematics prodigy.
Interesting, so that is the
man with whom I am competing.
I see. I must thoroughly
investigate him at once
and add him to the list.
After all,
I, Charles Augustus Milverton,
am thorough in my work.
How gruesome. While
determining the cause of death
is difficult due
to the explosion.
These stab wounds
indicate a professional.
We've come to
the same conclusion.
Well, you've been quiet.
Have you seen
anything we've missed?
Have you, Holmes?
Sherlock?
[HOLMES]
Yeah.
All eight were likely
victims of Jack the Ripper.
After stabbing them,
he used the explosion
as a decoy to get away.
Makes total sense. Right then,
we'll cordon off the area
and hunt him down.
Your insight is
appreciated, Holmes.
[footsteps]
[HOLMES]
Honestly,
such a thing does exist
as an inopportune truth.
The previous night's
events cooled tensions
between the Yard and
the Vigilance Committee,
as well as solving
the Ripper case.
This kind of sleight of hand,
only one person
could pull it off.
The guy fancies himself
some kind of Robin Hood!
What're you thinking,
Lord of Crime? This is madness!
[WILLIAM] So, that's the
direction you've chosen, Holmes.
Very well, but you must know,
the Yard certainly won't
be content allowing Jack
to remain at large, never.
Meaning, their
next move will be...
[ARTERTON grumbling]
William!
Yes?
[MORAN] Don't play dumb with me!
I demand an explanation!
[JACK] Again with the shouting?
What's wrong, Moran?
[WILLIAM] You're looking quite
fashionable, Maestro,
as always.
[JACK]
Of course, Young Will.
This is my main line
of work at the moment.
We wanted this to be
a surprise for you.
I'd say it worked.
The maestro is our new butler.
[MORAN]
Huh?!
The thought of Louis
keeping house for
two residences by himself.
Well, I couldn't bear it.
It's better this way.
He'll be able to take a
more active role in our plan.
Yes. Thank you,
Brother. How thoughtful.
[MORAN]
Thoughtful?!
[JACK] Truly, I look forward to
working alongside you.
[BONDE] What's the matter,
Moran? You look a little pale.
[MORAN]
Are you kidding me?!
[HERDER] Next time
on Moriarty the Patriot:
"The Riot in New Scotland Yard."